<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-05-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>New Blog Incoming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/05/17/new-blog-incoming.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/05/17/new-blog-incoming.html</id>
    <published>2018-05-17T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-17T23:26:24+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="new-blog-incoming"&gt;New Blog Incoming.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I've decided it's time to start rebuilding my website. You can probably tell it's struggling since my copyright is covering blog titles on the side and some of them are even missing now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I've decided about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It needs to be static&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It needs to be able to support growth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It needs to look good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Needs to be easy to add new blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="static"&gt;Static&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't want to pay for hosting and when it comes to my time I need to be able to keep the upkeep of this site to a minimum. Keeping the site static allows for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don't want to write it in straight HTML, Javascript and CSS. I'm probably going to keep to a css style I've copied somewhere off the web so I can keep my styling to a minimum and cut out a third of the work trying to think of what looks good in CSS. Plus I'm terrible at CSS so giving that job to someone else makes it so much easier for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to keep using Ruby because it's a really nice language to write in. The syntax is easy to read and I can go back and easily change it since my initial background is in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to have a bit more fun Javascript in my site now that I'm getting pretty awesome at it. I'll see if I can do some cool stuff that's interactive in the future. 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="growth"&gt;Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I need to be able to support that my blog will grow and that I might want to add future things etc. I've drawn up a few wireframes to have an idea of what I think I might do. But of course it might change depending on how I feel with the experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is what I'm thinking my initial About Me page will look like. Just a really simple page like I currently have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/about_me_page.png" alt="About Me Wireframe" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm thinking I'll have my Blog page in a more traditional blog style. Might even add an RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog_page.png" alt="Blog Wireframe" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I'm probably going to go with a pdf dump of my current resume since I really like the design of it. But I'm a little worried it might not match up with the rest of the design of my site so I'll have to figure out how I can make that flow and connect so it doesn't feel like an extreme transition. Maybe it means I'll need to tone down on the colours of my resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/resume_page.png" alt="Resume Wireframe" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="easy"&gt;Easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I need this blog to be easy to upkeep. I want to be able to just write a really quick blog post without too much thinking. Markdown is great for that so I'll be keep with my current frame work Middleman to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this happens soon and I'll keep this site updated till then.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Down the Rabbit Hole</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/03/29/down-the-rabbit-hole.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/03/29/down-the-rabbit-hole.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-17T22:52:57+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="down-the-rabbit-hole"&gt;Down the Rabbit Hole.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But I don’t want to go among mad people," Alice remarked.
"Oh, you can’t help that," said the Cat: "we’re all mad here. I’m mad. You’re mad."
"How do you know I’m mad?" said Alice.
"You must be," said the Cat, "or you wouldn’t have come here.”
― Lewis Carroll, Alice in Wonderland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="through-the-looking-glass"&gt;Through the Looking Glass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/121663/pexels-photo-121663.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;dpr=2&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;w=1260" alt="rabbit hole" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I met up with &lt;a href="https://github.com/chinamisr254" target="_blank"&gt;Joseph Hawkins&lt;/a&gt; a budding Ruby Developer from the US who I helped a little to find his way out of a rabbit hole in his code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, when I'm mentoring folks I find it interesting to see how folks are taught programming in different countries but with similar code assignments. And it's interesting to meet different people who learn at different speeds and do different things to solve the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some people might know, I've been mentoring my sister &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sophierose239" target="_blank"&gt;Sophie McDonald&lt;/a&gt; as well and one thing I find about mentoring is that I usually get asked similar questions. So I thought I should write something so that people who are aspiring to be programmers understand that even programmers who you think are "so above you" actually make mistakes and can get into similar situations like you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason I say this is because we all have similar fears and anxiety around learning something new or even old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en-gb"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I have been coding Ruby for over a decade and yet I just lost an hour because of something expecting a string when I was giving it a symbol.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ryan Bigg (@ryanbigg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ryanbigg/status/979578016127885312?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;30 March 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="brainfarts-and-rabbit-holes"&gt;Brainfarts and Rabbit Holes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a little embarrassed to admit this but I have "brainfarts" moments all the time and end up in rabbit holes so much so that I can end up wasting time writing silly code that is not even needed. Usually it happens when I'm stressed or I haven't had enough sleep or even from just the weather being awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if it's really important to make sure your mental health and physical health is in tip top shape if you want to function properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok.. soooo here is the problem I spent a bunch of time on that is really embarrassing for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an input field similar to the one below with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;select class="form-control" name="language" type="language" id="language"&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;option value=""&amp;gt;Select Language&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;option value="1"&amp;gt;English&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;option value="2"&amp;gt;French&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;option value="3"&amp;gt;Japanese&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/select&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;select class="form-control" name="language" type="language" id="language"&gt;
  &lt;option value=""&gt;Select Language&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="1"&gt;English&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="2"&gt;French&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="3"&gt;Japanese&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;/select&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for some reason I couldn't remember that you there is an ability to have a &lt;code&gt;selected&lt;/code&gt; option in html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started writing in Python a way to remove the language I was selecting from the list because it would showing up twice the way I had written the HTML originally. I had even spent some time writing tests to solve this. 😨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The messed up way looked like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;select class="form-control" name="language" type="language" id="language"&gt;
  &lt;option value="3"&gt;Japanese&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="1"&gt;English&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="2"&gt;French&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="3"&gt;Japanese&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;/select&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, open that drop down menu up and see what's going on and you'll see the issue I had. 😅 And I was trying to solve this problem in the backend with Python. WTF brain why aren't you working?!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a day or something and talking with a workmate, 🦆 I realised that all I needed to do was write the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;option value="3" selected&amp;gt;Japanese&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that it would turn out like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;select class="form-control" name="language" type="language" id="language"&gt;
  &lt;option value=""&gt;Select Language&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="1"&gt;English&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="2"&gt;French&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option value="3" selected=""&gt;Japanese&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;/select&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not even going to show you the Python I wrote for trying to solve this problem because no one should see that EVER. And also it's completely useless so if I put it anywhere I'm worried people might use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's been deleted forever now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fear-of-failure"&gt;Fear of Failure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/568027/pexels-photo-568027.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;h=650&amp;amp;w=940" alt="fear" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like a lot of questions on Stack Overflow, especially Javascript problems, are people having brainfart moments. I think it's important that those exist but sometimes they can lead us down the wrong path and we end up losing our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you do post on Stack Overflow (and I highly recommend you do at some stage) make sure you have tried to researched the problem thoroughly and checked to see if someone has asked a similar question. Believe me when I say, there is most likely an answer already written somewhere about the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overcome the fear of failure because the first step to success is to at least try.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don't feel bad if you don't know something. Just Google it! Even if you feel it's something you should already know. Learning something over and over again is calling practicing and it helps you become better by committing it to your long term memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what I'm trying to say with this post, is that everyone has these moments even people who have been coding for years. So if you are ever feeling like you can't do it just remember we are all have the ability to do it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debugging the slow way.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/03/05/debugging-the-slow-way.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/03/05/debugging-the-slow-way.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-17T22:52:57+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="debugging-the-slow-way"&gt;Debugging the Slow Way.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/813469/pexels-photo-813469.jpeg?w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=2&amp;amp;auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb" alt="Snail" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="changing-languages"&gt;Changing languages.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in my &lt;a href="/2017/12/18/future-plans-in-self-development.html" target="_blank"&gt;last article I wrote how I was doing Python nowadays instead of Ruby.&lt;/a&gt; 😭&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's been a lot easier than I originally thought it would be and I would say that a nice 😇 (or maybe not so nice 😈) side effect has meant my Javascript has significantly improved since the move too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason and the driving force for this has been the old skool and super boring way I've been debugging my problems in Python. There are tools similar to Ruby's Pry in Python such as PDB (Python De Bug???) but they are totally not the same or as flexible and that's mainly been why most of my cursing at work has been around "ahhhh damn you Python being so shitty!!!" whilst all my co-workers laugh at my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQw4w9WgXcQ" target="_blank"&gt;never ending adoration for Ruby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="back-to-school"&gt;Back to School.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I've been using &lt;code&gt;Print()&lt;/code&gt; A LOT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;code&gt;console.log()&lt;/code&gt; has been my go to for Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no updating the page and waiting for pry to stop my stuff and solving the problem in the console like I did for Ruby. I now have to think and refresh and then check it and then refresh and think and ALL THE THINGS I DIDN'T HAVE TO DO BEFORE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't even remember what Pry was like anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, going old skool can definitely improve your coding and if you really don't want to go to the trouble of adding Pry into your script/project for Ruby you can always use handy dandy &lt;code&gt;put&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding! ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Future Plans in Self Development.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/18/future-plans-in-self-development.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/18/future-plans-in-self-development.html</id>
    <published>2017-12-18T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-18T22:26:04+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="future-plans-in-self-development"&gt;Future Plans in Self Development.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/new_years.jpeg" alt="Happy New Years" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="changes-in-my-personal-development"&gt;Changes in my personal development.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday as I was scrolling through all my work in Github I remember reading this really awful article (won't even bother linking it) about how your Github profile is meant to determine how hard working you are in tech. This is a complete and utter fallacy by the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it did get me thinking. I have a lot of public repos that are on display stupidly without licences but I guess they are automatically covered by copyright in Australia/Sweden (hopefully?) but still it's concerning. So I started changing them all to private repos. It took a while to do only because I had something like 30 repos of unfinished work. And I also had a lot of forks of other people's work that I was going to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do work on private repos most of the time people can't see that on your Github so that's why I said it's a really stupid thing for someone to write in an article. Plus some of us use Bitbucket. 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah if you haven't got licences on your work make sure you do that and don't take to heart that some people might seeing Github as a measure for how hard working you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="plans-for-this-website"&gt;Plans for this website.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning on trying to write more next year on this blog. I know I've released a few articles here and there but I think maybe I should try and focus a bit more on what I've learnt especially since I'm now working in Python nowadays. Goodbye Ruby! 😭&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be technical from now on. Although, I think it's important for me to focus on the social aspects of being in a dev community so this is a place for me to express those views too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also decided to update this site to make it a bit more fresh but I think that might take a fair bit of time. Now that I've sorted out the backend to make writing articles super easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm also hoping to make this site a bit more interactive but I think that's going to mean I'll need to make the switch over to HTTPS and I still need to figure that out. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hopefully, in the New Year I'll live up to these super high expectations I've set for myself since I haven't been super involved in the physical community as much nowadays. 😉&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Home Away from Home.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/11/23/a-home-away-from-home.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/11/23/a-home-away-from-home.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-23T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-18T22:25:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="a-home-away-from-home"&gt;A Home Away from Home.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t think of anything that excites a greater sense of childlike wonder than to be in a country where you are ignorant of almost everything. Suddenly you are five years old again. You can’t read anything, you have only the most rudimentary sense of how things work, you can’t even reliably cross a street without endangering your life. Your whole existence becomes a series of interesting guesses. – Bill Bryson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="when-imposter-syndrome-becomes-real"&gt;When Imposter Syndrome becomes Real.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November 2016, I made a &lt;a href="/2016/12/19/how-to-move-overseas-from-australia.html" target="_blank"&gt;trip from Australia to Sweden&lt;/a&gt; in order to find life, love and a hope to further my career in Tech. After a series of unfortunate events and achieving a few of the goals I had set out to do I ended up feeling broken, alone and an imposter in my own supposed field of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I felt I had reached the Imposter Syndrome mountain peak. I was and still am in  a country where I am essentially 5 years old again. I find it difficult to communicate to people, I find it difficult for people to understand me and the ultimate problem that kept me up at night during the summertime was the inability to have and keep a job in a country I thought would be my new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I tried to keep a positive attitude to my then current situation, the reality was I had no idea what the hell I was even doing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Australia, I thought I had made a good role model for Women in Tech within the Ruby community. I was known for doing my work well, I was known for taking on new challenges easily, I was known for talking about things that I thought I knew about and I was seen as a good mentor and role model for Women in Tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward and there I was sitting on a couch somewhere in Sweden waiting for my partner to come home in order to save me from myself. I found I had become reliant on him to help me. I needed him to pay for food. I needed him to keep a roof over our heads. I needed him to be happy so that I could have the most basic things in my life right then. He was the one who paid the bills and I was the one who sat at home all day trying to solve the problem of what I thought was my own doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="so-what-was-i-actually-doing"&gt;So What Was I Actually Doing?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was and still am passionate, I was and still am practicing and I was and still am trying to be part of a community. I was doing all this whilst dealing with mental health issues that were doing my head in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I was depressed and anxious most of the time during the summer of 2017. I was desperately trying to organise job interviews everyday in order to prove that I could actually do what I did in Australia, here in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I complained to my partner that I couldn't keep doing this he would respond "You aren't sick. You just need a job and then everything will be better."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I kept myself busy, ignoring the fact that there were tears constantly streaming down my face, in order to prove to myself that eventually after the long and tiresome journey of job searching I will have made it to where I want to be in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="was-i-passionate"&gt;Was I passionate?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/2016/04/16/how-to-find-a-job-in-tech.html" target="_blank"&gt;'Passion is what you need. Clearly, if you had passion you
would have a job by now.'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I wrote last year and said naively to students at a University in Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;'Are you working on something now?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesssssss! Yes, I was and still am. I was working on myself. I was working on being part of an open source community &lt;a href="www.if-me.org" target="_blank"&gt;if-me.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;'Are you keeping yourself busy with what you love?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesssssss! Yes, I was and still am. I was doing coding everyday. Of course I love it. I want to continue doing this, Alexia of the Past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;'Seriously, people who are passionate about what they love are the ones that get jobs. They get emails all the time from people asking to hire them. If you aren’t getting emails from people asking you to work for them then something is wrong.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yessss! Yes, I do and still do (maybe more so now that I have a job). I would get emails but not the emails I wanted. I received emails from recruiters who didn't know what I was capable of or what I was after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to break out of the mould of a Ruby on Rails developer. I had to convince myself to come to the realisation that I needed to expand my skills more or that I was capable of doing those other languages like Python but I needed to be confident and that was something I felt could not do at that moment in time. So I needed to fake it, fake confidence!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to say 'yes' more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also received emails from people who said "I was not senior enough" and emails from people who said I needed to "learn more Swedish" and emails from people who thanked me for running &lt;a href="http://railsgirls.com/stockholm_032017.html" target="_blank"&gt;Rails Girls in Stockholm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The passion was clearly there. And it still is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="practicing-what-i-dont-know"&gt;Practicing what I don't know.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still believe I don't know anything. I know this. No one is capable of knowing everything. I've come to another country and essentially put myself in a situation where I've pretty much demoted myself and I'm back to being a child reliant on someone else to help me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which reminds me, that I read an article by &lt;a href="https://medium.freecodecamp.org/5-key-learnings-from-the-post-bootcamp-job-search-9a07468d2331" target="_blank"&gt;Felix Feng about how he managed to get a job in tech&lt;/a&gt; and my overall view after reading that article with salary was that it was certainly not tied to experience at all but rather how confident you can be. So whilst I say "I've demoted myself" I had clearly demoted myself in terms of confidence rather than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code tests, whilst I've had to do many of them, I had taken to task that I had to fix code tests I had supposedly failed at rather than do new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reason being was that it saved me time, energy and confidence which could be spent on certain companies, which may or may not have given me the job regardless of if I completed a code test or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My method helped me become a better programmer in that I could go over code I had clearly done in a stressed environment, look at it and figure out where I had gone wrong. I could do this in a way that helped me but also it gave me the opportunity to ask others to review and help me find the errors of my ways so I could learn from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting for me in that some people thought my code was perfect whilst others found parts of it that were completely wrong according to them. And this makes me wonder if code tests are essentially a waste of time for everyone involved because it justifies people's bias when they know who has done the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="being-part-of-the-local-community-isnt-always-easy"&gt;Being part of the local community isn't always easy.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The easiest and best way to get a job is through someone you know already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stockholm shuts down in the Summertime. And this means, so do opportunities to network. People go on holidays and a lot of tasks that are normally easy to do become extremely difficult. It's a cultural thing, for sure! And another story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't speak Swedish, it can be difficult to bond with people. I'm part of many Swedish code communities and most of the time I am unable to contribute or even understand what is going on due to my inability to understand or speak Swedish. It's thing I don't experience in the &lt;a href="ruby-berlin.slack.com" target="_blank"&gt;Berlin slack group&lt;/a&gt; that I'm part of. But it could be I'm more ingrained into Swedish culture than German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to fix that particular issue is to magically become fluent in a language I don't know very well. I know I'm better than most people (most being the rest of the world) but it's not enough and it's a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been learning Swedish very slowly and maybe I should motivate myself to learn it faster but it's difficult when people hear my Australian accent through my Swedish and automatically talk to me in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.internations.org/expat-insider/2017/ease-of-settling-in-index-39187" target="_blank"&gt;Sweden isn't exactly known for being the best place for ease of settling in.&lt;/a&gt; This might shock some people who believe the hype of Sweden being the best country in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all these problems, I've had with the community in Stockholm/Sweden hasn't stopped me from trying to participate and meet people. I organised &lt;a href="http://railsgirls.com/stockholm_032017.html" target="_blank"&gt;Rails Girls in March 2017&lt;/a&gt; for the first time in 2 years and I met a lot of lovely people willing to help make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my contribution to &lt;a href="www.if-me.org" target="_blank"&gt;if-me.org&lt;/a&gt; in offering Swedish as a language was &lt;a href="/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html" target="_blank"&gt;made possible by people in Sweden.&lt;/a&gt; So help is definitely there, you just need to find the right way of asking for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a similar experience I had the last time I was in Stockholm, in 2013 when my friend Isak helped me out by letting me stay at his home for a while. I was in a similar job searching situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I would say that job searching now it's a lot more difficult due to the the political climate change around foreigners that's been brewing for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="so-whats-the-advice"&gt;So what's the advice?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd say keep going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take my advice from the first article I wrote about &lt;a href="/2016/04/16/how-to-find-a-job-in-tech.html" target="_blank"&gt;How to Get a Job in Tech&lt;/a&gt; but also take it with a massive pinch of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a job is hard. You need to look after your mental health as that's a major priority. Check out &lt;a href="/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html" target="_blank"&gt;my thoughts on Mental Health in Sweden.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most importantly be &lt;strong&gt;kind to yourself and if it gets tough ask for help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.&lt;/strong&gt; I eventually got a job at Star Stable Entertainment ❤️🦄&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing if-me.org in Swedish</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html</id>
    <published>2017-09-13T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-21T13:05:13+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="announcing-if-meorg-in-swedish"&gt;Announcing if-me.org in Swedish.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexia McDonald is a developer from Melbourne, Australia who moved to Sweden. She joined if-me.org because she wanted to help her sister with RGSoC. She also wanted contribute to an open source project to further develop her skills. She led the Swedish translations with the help from &lt;a href="https://github.com/olleolleolle" target="_blank"&gt;Olle Jonsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/drenmi" target="_blank"&gt;Ted Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Marcus_Pazienza" target="_blank"&gt;Marcus Liverfalk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/clearminds" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Eriksson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*0N3ko6q4wc7HiJuLorSZxA.png" alt="Swedish town" /&gt;
Picture of Waterfronts in Sweden, taken from &lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Waterfronts_in_Sweden_14_2010.jpg"&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-is-mental-health-important-to-you"&gt;Why is mental health important to you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer means we use our brain as our main tool. It's super important to remain healthy in order to be a great programmer and being healthy includes looking after your mental health. Mental health is especially important when living in a country that isn't yours. This is something I've been struggling with in Sweden since it's not my "home-ground". My personal struggles around the language, gender diversity in tech and my personal relationships have all had a massive impact on my anxiety levels which have been pretty high since I decided to take the plunge out of my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-is-mental-health-perceived-and-treated-in-sweden"&gt;How is mental health perceived and treated in Sweden?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my personal experience of living in Sweden, most people tend to keep to themselves and anyone seen complaining is rather frowned upon. Keeping a positive facade is something I find Swedes pride themselves on and showing any negative emotions is seen as a sign of weakness to others but also themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've noticed in Sweden it's normal to shun people who are sad or negative either because you don't know what to say or you don't want to be sucked into the 'drama'. It's a thing to avoid people here. No one wants to say anything and no one wants to look at anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workplaces, although they are touted as a place for flexibility and equality can end up being a breeding grounds for burnout or as it's known here in Sweden "hitting the wall".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I'm not sure how people here do it but it's definitely something I've really struggled with and hopefully some of the people who experience the things I mention can benefit from this site being translated into a language they are familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-did-you-want-to-participate-in-translating-if-meorg"&gt;Why did you want to participate in translating if-me.org?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, I wanted to translate if-me.org into Swedish for foreigners who lived here. Like me, I felt they might also struggle and whilst some of these people might not know English as a second language I find providing Swedish would be a good start since &lt;a href="http://www.stockholm.se/sfi"&gt;SFI (free Swedish lessons)&lt;/a&gt; is available in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But later, it occurred to me that translating something into Swedish would blow the myth that you need to know fluent Swedish in order to work as a programmer here in Sweden out of the water. Translating if-me.org has given me an opportunity to learn new words and phrases in Swedish that I had not come across yet and it's done that in a less aggressive manner than doing SFI because coding is something I actually enjoy doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/swedish_site.png" alt="swedish site" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="were-there-any-interesting-challenges-you-came-across-while-translating"&gt;Were there any interesting challenges you came across while translating?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant stream of comments about what the correct translation of certain words were, was funny but also taxing at times. I actually had to take a few days off before getting back into it because it was a lot of work to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great example of where I made a funny/tragic mistake is when I wrote “Allierade som kan se din strategi och tagga egna ögon med det.” which means “Allies who can see your strategy and take their own eyes with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, a huge thanks once again to &lt;a href="https://github.com/olleolleolle" target="_blank"&gt;Olle Jonsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/drenmi" target="_blank"&gt;Ted Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Marcus_Pazienza" target="_blank"&gt;Marcus Liverfalk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/clearminds" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Eriksson&lt;/a&gt; for their hard work reading and correcting my Swedish 💜.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know how your experience is going with our Swedish site. If you want to see our app in your language, contact us at &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#102;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#102;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
