<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-09-13T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing if-me.org in Swedish</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/13/announcing-if-me-org-in-swedish.html</id>
    <published>2017-09-13T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T21:20:11+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="announcing-if-meorg-in-swedish"&gt;Announcing if-me.org in Swedish.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexia McDonald is a developer from Melbourne, Australia who moved to Sweden. She joined if-me.org because she wanted to help her sister with RGSoC. She also wanted contribute to an open source project to further develop her skills. She led the Swedish translations with the help from &lt;a href="https://github.com/olleolleolle" target="_blank"&gt;Olle Jonsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/drenmi" target="_blank"&gt;Ted Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Marcus_Pazienza" target="_blank"&gt;Marcus Liverfalk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/clearminds" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Eriksson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/swedish_site.png" alt="swedish site" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-is-mental-health-important-to-you"&gt;Why is mental health important to you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer means we use our brain as our main tool. It's super important to remain healthy in order to be a great programmer and being healthy includes looking after your mental health. Mental health is especially important when living in a country that isn't yours. This is something I've been struggling with in Sweden since it's not my "home-ground". My personal struggles around the language, gender diversity in tech and my personal relationships have all had a massive impact on my anxiety levels which have been pretty high since I decided to take the plunge out of my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-is-mental-health-perceived-and-treated-in-sweden"&gt;How is mental health perceived and treated in Sweden?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my personal experience of living in Sweden, most people tend to keep to themselves and anyone seen complaining is rather frowned upon. Keeping a positive facade is something I find Swedes pride themselves on and showing any negative emotions is seen as a sign of weakness to others but also themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've noticed in Sweden it's normal to shun people who are sad or negative either because you don't know what to say or you don't want to be sucked into the 'drama'. It's a thing to avoid people here. No one wants to say anything and no one wants to look at anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workplaces, although they are touted as a place for flexibility and equality can end up being a breeding grounds for burnout or as it's known here in Sweden "hitting the wall".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I'm not sure how people here do it but it's definitely something I've really struggled with and hopefully some of the people who experience the things I mention can benefit from this site being translated into a language they are familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-did-you-want-to-participate-in-translating-if-meorg"&gt;Why did you want to participate in translating if-me.org?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, I wanted to translate if-me.org into Swedish for foreigners who lived here. Like me, I felt they might also struggle and whilst some of these people might not know English as a second language I find providing Swedish would be a good start since &lt;a href="http://www.stockholm.se/sfi"&gt;SFI (free Swedish lessons)&lt;/a&gt; is available in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But later, it occurred to me that translating something into Swedish would blow the myth that you need to know fluent Swedish in order to work as a programmer here in Sweden out of the water. Translating if-me.org has given me an opportunity to learn new words and phrases in Swedish that I had not come across yet and it's done that in a less aggressive manner than doing SFI because coding is something I actually enjoy doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="were-there-any-interesting-challenges-you-came-across-while-translating"&gt;Were there any interesting challenges you came across while translating?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant stream of comments about what the correct translation of certain words were, was funny but also taxing at times. I actually had to take a few days off before getting back into it because it was a lot of work to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great example of where I made a funny/tragic mistake is when I wrote “Allierade som kan se din strategi och tagga egna ögon med det.” which means “Allies who can see your strategy and take their own eyes with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, a huge thanks once again to &lt;a href="https://github.com/olleolleolle" target="_blank"&gt;Olle Jonsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/drenmi" target="_blank"&gt;Ted Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Marcus_Pazienza" target="_blank"&gt;Marcus Liverfalk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/clearminds" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Eriksson&lt;/a&gt; for their hard work reading and correcting my Swedish 💜.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know how your experience is going with our Swedish site. If you want to see our app in your language, contact us at &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#102;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#102;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Move Overseas From Australia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/19/how-to-move-overseas-from-australia.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/19/how-to-move-overseas-from-australia.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T18:03:39+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="how-to-move-overseas-from-australia"&gt;How to move overseas from Australia&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/freedom_moving.jpeg" alt="woman being free" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="get-rid-of-everything"&gt;Get rid of everything&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When moving overseas it's best to get rid of as much as you possibly can. Really love that awesome bicycle you own? Sorry, it has to go. If there are small things you want to keep you can always post them to your new address overseas but if you can do without it then get rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ways to rid yourself of crap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sell it on Gumtree or through Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give it away to friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If it's useless meaningless crap throw it out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donate to charity (they sometimes even come pick it up for you!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on selling your crap remember to give yourself a few weeks to do it. A lot of people who buy things off the internet are useless at turning up or even following through with their purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="disconnecting-utilities"&gt;Disconnecting utilities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="watergaselectricity"&gt;Water/Gas/Electricity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very simple to do. Just call them up a few days before you leave to disconnect the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="health-insurance"&gt;Health insurance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently with AHM and if you call them up they can put your health insurance on hold for a year. Very practical. If you come back for a holiday (to Australia) you can just restart and you don't have to do the waiting periods again. You can also put it back on hold any time. Very handy indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can find health insurance that includes travel insurance that's also a bonus. Lucky for me I found a credit card that throw it in compliments of your spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="internet"&gt;Internet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was actually a kicker for me. I ended up having to pay extra because I forgot to read the fine print for cancellation. Some internet companies &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; TPG &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; want you to cancel at least 30 days before. If you are leaving before 30 days you might have to pay a cancellation fee unless you find some kind soul to take over your services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wes.id.au/2014/02/cancel-tpg-adsl/"&gt;This person's website was very helpful when cancelling my TPG account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="mobile-services"&gt;Mobile services&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know you are going to leave sometime in the future make sure you call your mobile provider every couple of months to complain about the shitty service of your postpaid contract account. If you do this it will provide a very easy way for you to cancel the contract without incurring expensive costs that are usually associated with contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it's time to leave just explain that you wish to cancel your contract due to extremely awful service and you'll usually have your service either heavily discounted or waived completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked up a super expensive travel SIM as I was travelling to a bunch of different countries on the way. It seemed like the best option. I changed my Australian number to ALDI because it was on $5 to park my number there for a year better than some of the other telecommunications companies. My travel SIM ended up costing me more than $70 for the month because Israel got very expensive. It would have been ok if I hadn't gone to Israel. I've now switched to a SIM card in the country I am in now for practical reasons. But it's still temp at the moment due to the lack of personal number at the beginning of my arrival in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="finances"&gt;Finances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to pay your finances ahead of time. Exchange rates are terrible and you don't want to be that person who's traveller cheques aren't accepted. No one does cheques anymore coz they are super lame!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have some alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get yourself a credit card with "No foreign transaction fees on online or overseas purchases"
I had a look around the &lt;a href="http://www.bankwest.com.au/personal/credit-cards/compare-credit-cards/zero-mastercard-no-annual-fee-credit-cards"&gt;Bankwest Zero Platinum Mastercard&lt;/a&gt; was the best one I could find for my situation and it also offered complimentary travel insurance. Make sure you look up a credit card compare site to find the best deal for your scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set up a money transfer account&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.xe.com/xemoneytransfer/au/?WT.seg_1=XTR-400x30-XHOM-ADH-AU-V01-161031"&gt;XE Money Transfer&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to easily transfer money between your Australian account and your new overseas bank account. It's a little bit of a hassle to setup and they might randomly call you in the middle of the night from some foreign country to confirm you're a legit person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;a href="https://transferwise.com/"&gt;Transfer Wise&lt;/a&gt; as well. It's a much nicer web experience and verification takes less time too! You can easily set it up with Facebook or your Google account. Either way I'll end up using one of the two to transfer money to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tell your banks you are going overseas&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set up paperless statements if you haven't already done this&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you have access to Paypal overseas. I found out the hard way when I lost my SIM card that I couldn't access my accounts because I had done 2 factor auth with my Australian phone number. Yup, good job me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="getting-stuff-done-in-sweden"&gt;Getting stuff done in Sweden&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as you have found out if your visa has been approved your next step should be to set up an appointment date to have your fingerprints and photo to be taken at the immigration office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as you get this card from the immigration office you need to go to the Tax office and ask for a personal number. If at all possible try and get a Tax ID card from them on the same day. They may not be able to do it in which case you will probably have to wait a week and then come back to get the ID card. You can also hand in your forms for Försäkringskassan which you will have to fill in if you are staying in Sweden longer than a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these processes may take more than 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have a personal number and an ID card you can apply for a bank account. Bank accounts in Sweden seem to be very difficult to get if you are not a Swede. They don't seem to care if you earn money or that you need to pay people. If you aren't Swedish you can't have a bank account. So make sure you have a personal number and an ID card and you should be able to get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren't staying for a year then a organisation number should be ok to get a bank account at some banks. They might give you a maestro bank card (which can be pretty useless) to access your account but they probably won't give you internet banking. Swedbank and Nordea are known for being really difficult when it comes to this. I've had success at SEB in the past so if you find yourself not being able to have financial independence at other banks then try SEB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="packing-your-suitcase"&gt;Packing your suitcase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was travelling to other countries on the way to Sweden. I needed to make sure that my suitcase was going to be compliant with all the airlines weight limits. I had a goal of making my suitcase 20kg even though with my first flight I was allowed 32kg. I looked up the weight limits for all the different airlines that I was flying with. Some ranged from 32kg to 20kg and I decided that it was probably best to aim for 20kg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;** Turns out I still had to pay for extra baggage on my way to Prague because it wasn't specified very clearly on the website. Thank you Air Berlin! **&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I donated a lot of clothes to charities so that I could reach my weight limit and with some things I really wanted to keep but didn't need straight away I chucked into a box for shipping at a later date. I still haven't the box sent but I plan on sending it through Pack and Send as they seemed the cheapest when I looked up shipping under 30kg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the unfortunate scenario of travelling to different countries with different weather. I was really hoping that I would be able to pull of the 'no winter clothes' but it fucking started snowing in Sweden before I left Australia so I had to prepare. I had to pack sandals, winter shoes and my normal shoes. I had to pack a jacket for winter and of course my jacket in Australia is really shit because Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Awesome Tools for Windows</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/04/24/awesome-tools-for-windows.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/04/24/awesome-tools-for-windows.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-24T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T18:02:55+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="awesome-tools-for-windows"&gt;Awesome Tools for Windows.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Asked about the fact that Apple's iTunes software for Windows
computers was extremely popular, Jobs joked, 'It's like giving a glass of ice
water to somebody in hell.”
― Walter Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="open-the-windows"&gt;Open the Windows.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started University with the idea of being a programmer I had no
idea how easy I could make my life if I had just installed Linux. The computers
we were taught on pretty much all had Windows installed on them and only
some of the really serious people in my course had switched to Linux. I was
scared to the jump ship and knowing that my craptop had &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardware_virtualization" target="_blank"&gt;hardware virtualisation&lt;/a&gt; disabled it wouldn't be possible to switch back quickly if I
wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I met &lt;a href="https://github.com/brendanzab" target="_blank"&gt;Brendan&lt;/a&gt; who offered up his awesome
knowledge to me about the possibility of making Windows run a little bit like Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.giphy.com/cOWNPwDDh1tYs.gif" alt="&amp;quot;Mmm chocolate&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="everything-is-better-with-chocolate"&gt;Everything is better with Chocolate.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows, the land where open source software pages look like you are going to
download Malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Chocolatey is a package manager for Windows (like apt-get or yum
but for Windows). It was designed to be a decentralized framework for quickly
installing applications and tools that you need. It is built on the NuGet
infrastructure currently using PowerShell as its focus for delivering packages
from the distros to your door, err computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a must if you want to live the Windows life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/" target="_blank"&gt;chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; to free yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="simba-cmder"&gt;Simba, Cmder…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can have an awesome console on Windows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Cmder is a software package created out of pure frustration over the absence of nice
console emulators on Windows. It is based on amazing software, and spiced up
with the Monokai color scheme and a custom prompt layout. Looking sexy from the
start."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, welcome to the wonderful world of
&lt;a href="http://cmder.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Cmder&lt;/a&gt;. The place where no one knows how to pronouce
it and honestly we don't care because it's got multi tabs. YAY!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download this sweet terminal just go into what you currently have… either
Powershell or CMD and type in the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install cmder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pin it to your toolbar and you're good to go for the rest
of your Windows career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*If it doesn't work you are probably missing &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-au/download/details.aspx?id=48145" target="_blank"&gt;Visual C++ Redistributable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.giphy.com/szmmbDDpS67LO.gif" alt="&amp;quot;Simba dance&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="go-crazy"&gt;Go crazy.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are set to go and can download all the things! These two tools are
awesome and make life so much easier. There are heaps of awesome things you
could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could install &lt;strong&gt;Git:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you want to run &lt;strong&gt;Bash on Cmder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Open Cmder, then click on the new tab menu, selecting the Setup tasks... option.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/cmder-task-settings.png" alt="cmder setup" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new task by clicking the + button, and enter the following settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Git Bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task parameters:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;/icon "%ProgramFiles(x86)%\Git\etc\git.ico" /dir "%userprofile%"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commands:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;""C:\Program Files (x86)\Git\bin\sh.exe" --login -i"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you want to code some &lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;choco install ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal favourite is to add my &lt;strong&gt;SSH keys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Open Git Bash
in cmder. Follow Github's&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/generating-an-ssh-key/#platform-windows" target="_blank"&gt;instructions
for setting up your SSH keys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;using ssh-keygen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The list goes on…&lt;/em&gt;
Check all the packages on &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/packages" target="_blank"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-au/commandline/wsl/about" target="_blank"&gt;This might soon be obsolete information as Windows has this plan where they make Linux work on Windows for realz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.giphy.com/l41m1CuaT5Oy624Ra.gif" alt="&amp;quot;Welcome to the interwebs&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to find a Job in Tech</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/04/16/how-to-find-a-job-in-tech.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/04/16/how-to-find-a-job-in-tech.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T18:02:55+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="how-to-find-a-job-in-tech"&gt;How to find a Job in Tech.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You're still working on that website that you were working on 4 weeks ago?
That’s a lot of work for one website. There must be a lot of
programmers because if you think about how many websites there are, that’s a lot.
- Flatmate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="too-many-websites"&gt;Too many websites.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s weird how I hear from people I went to University with or
people I run into who have a tech degree and they can’t find a job. That flatmate
is correct. We need a lot of devs to take care of the internet. We
don’t have enough developers at the moment to take care of all those websites
and we are going to need a lot more if the population keeps growing and every
man, woman, child and their doge 🐕 wants a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="but-there-are-no-jobs"&gt;But there are no jobs.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fallacy that there are no jobs in tech. I’m going
to give it to you really, really blunt. The reason you can’t get a job in tech is
because you’re not trying. Looking on seek.com.au or whirlpool is not where you
are going to find a job. Sure, there are jobs on there but they are not the jobs
I suspect you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="are-you-passionate"&gt;Are you passionate?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passion is what you need. Clearly, if you had passion you
would have a job by now. Are you working on something now? Are you keeping
yourself busy with what you love? Seriously, people who are passionate about
what they love get jobs. They get emails all the time from people asking to hire
them. If you aren’t getting emails from people asking you to work for them then
something is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="practice-what-you-dont-know"&gt;Practice what you don't know.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, congratulations you just got out of University
and you know absolutely nothing. Trust me, you know nothing! If you haven’t been
pursuing your passion outside of University, then I’m telling you now you are at
square one. University only teaches you the basics. It teaches you stuff that is
10 years old that you aren’t ever going to use (maybe some of it). I bet you
they did not teach you about writing tests for your code and if they did well you
got lucky. Practice code outside of university and learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.giphy.com/ypO01RIuQ3tHW.gif" alt="&amp;quot;Nothing is impossible&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="be-part-of-the-community"&gt;Be part of the community.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest and best way to get a job is through
someone you know already. If you don’t know anyone who works in tech then you
aren’t any closer to your goal of getting a job. You need to be part of the
community and be noticed. Plus, this is a really good way to learn what is new
and trendy at the moment and a great way to find a mentor who can help you when
things get tough. Being part of the community gives you a way to find new
projects to work on, meet people in tech, help others and be passionate about
the things you love!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="how"&gt;How?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get started by working on a project on &lt;a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or
attending Hackathons. You can also work on that awesome personal project you
have been thinking about for ages but haven't actually done yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be part of the community you can attend meetups, follow slack channels for
programming communities, IRC or forums. Reading and watching videos on the
latest tech innovations is also a really good way to increase your knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there isn't anything you feel you can be part of you can always start your
own either at university or through other avenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.giphy.com/wCiFka9RsSW9W.gif" alt="&amp;quot;Yes you can&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>About me</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/01/01/about-me.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/01/01/about-me.html</id>
    <published>2016-01-01T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T18:02:55+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="about-me"&gt;About Me&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I'm Alexia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a developer who has mainly worked in startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a speaker of tech and mentor for women in tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/duck.gif" alt="picture of me" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm currently living in Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can read about some of the things I've been up to and stuff I've learnt along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want, you are most welcome to be my Twitter follower &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thespacepony" target="_blank"&gt;@TheSpacepony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emoji Game Station</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/15/emoji-game.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/15/emoji-game.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-15T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T18:02:55+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="emoji-game-station"&gt;Emoji Game Station.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where you can easily find The Melbourne Emoji Game which was originally posted on my Twitter Page &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thespacepony" target="_blank"&gt;@TheSpacepony&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped out of University to pursue a career in tech. I was studying a &lt;a href="http://www2.rmit.edu.au/Courses/pdf/bp215.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Bachelor of Information Technology majoring in Games and Graphics Programming at RMIT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this game after being inspired by a similar riddle for the London Tube, which was widely credited for driving the internet to distraction. I ended up driving Melbourne to that &lt;a href="http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/how-well-do-you-know-melbournes-train-stations-take-this-emoji-quiz-20150714-gic1p0.html" target="_blank"&gt;same distraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-york-emoji-game"&gt;New York Emoji Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/newyork_emoji.jpg" alt="New York emoji game" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="sydney-emoji-game"&gt;Sydney Emoji Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/sydney_emoji.jpg" alt="Sydney emoji game" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="melbourne-emoji-game"&gt;Melbourne Emoji Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/melb_emoji.jpg" alt="Melbourne emoji game" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="melbourne-emoji-game-part-2"&gt;Melbourne Emoji Game: Part 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/melb_emoji_hard.jpg" alt="Melbourne harder emoji game" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="stockholm-emoji-game"&gt;Stockholm Emoji Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/stockholm_emoji.jpg" alt="Stockholm emoji game" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
